

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER · EVENT STREAMING

73 Forest Run Blvd, Concord, ON, L4K5J6, Canada

□ (+1) 647-219-6236 | waismanedward@gmail.com | □ eddyv | □ edwardvaisman

Professional Summary

Software developer with 4 years of professional experience and a potent interest for event-driven systems. Proficiency in operating multi-region distributed streaming platforms like apache kafka on aws. Extensive software development life-cycle experience exercised from start to finish along with prominent communication skills and constructive attitude.

Experience

Tucows Toronto, ON

Kafka Administrator Nov. 2020 - Present

- Build, secure, and maintain the overall Kafka infrastructure.
- · Build the automation to provision, maintain, and monitor all aspects of the Kafka environment via infrastructure as code.
- Design, implement, and operate multi-datacenter Kafka infrastructure.
- Build monitoring dashboards and visualization to provide real-time insights and observability of Kafka clusters connectivity, security and performance.
- Identify bottlenecks and tune to optimize Kafka performance and throughput.
- Ensure all disaster recovery protocols are tested with routine backup and recovery exercises.

BMO Financial Group Toronto, ON

SR. APPLICATION DEVELOPER

Oct. 2020 - Oct. 2020

May. 2016 - Sept. 2018

- Key contributor to the banks customer intellegience platform; Responsible for deriving and implementing a solution which will help provide the business with a complete view of their customers and to deliver pleasent experiences in near real-time
- Onboarded, trained, and mentored new developers, ensuring they are comfortable and self sufficient in dealing large distributed systems. Adhering to all best practices in code management (Adopting Git Flow), code deployment (Dockerizing your applications), as well as EDA (Event-Driven Architecture).
- Designed & implemented a real-time data pipeline that is field level encrypted to allow for data transfer between our kafka cluster on-premises and our kafka cluster in the cloud(AWS).

BMO Financial Group Toronto, ON

 Developer
 Sept. 2018 - Oct. 2020

- Helped build real-time streaming data pipelines to reliably get data between systems and applications.
- Built real-time streaming applications that transform & react to streams of data.
- Automated approaches to streamline and integrate technological processes and/or systems to improve operational efficiency and effectiveness
- Conceived and wrote detailed software implementations while ensuring that their code adhere to the security, logging, error handling, and performance standards and non-functional requirements.
- Demonstrated detailed application of software knowledge through the production of a series of projects including:
 Application Development (Java, KafkaStreams, KafkaConnect); Other (XSLT/XML, JSON, AVRO, WSDL, HTML, CSS3, Javascript, React, Git, Ansible, Bamboo);

Viacoremedia Toronto, ON

• Developed excellent time-management skills through deadline driven projects and tasks.

- Responsible for management of web pages, email hosting, web hosting.
- Responsible for creating scalable robust web pages; information gathering, planning, developing, testing, debugging code and designing
- Created multiple scalable, responsive, and robust PPC web pages with high conversion rates.
- · Worked with clients and project managers to determine the scope and goals of their web pages such as SEO Optimization.
- Gathered and analyzed data for website optimization and presentation to the client.
- Demonstrated detailed application of software knowledge through the production of a series of projects including: Animations (CSS3, JQuery); Scripting (PHP, Javascript, JQuery, Google Apps Scripts); CMS(Wordpress).

Skills

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

Programming Java, C#, C/C++, Turing, XNA Game Studio, Linux, Python.

Web HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap Framework, Express with Node.JS, PHP, MYSQL, WordPress.

Big Data Confluent Kafka, Kafka Connect, Avro.

Cloud AWS S3, AWS Secrets Manager, Serverless Framework. **DevOps Tools** GitLab, GitHub, BitBucket, Ansible, Bamboo, Maven.

Languages English, Russian.

Education

York University Toronto, Canada

B.Sc., Spec. Hons. Computer Science (Software Development)

Sept. 2013 - April. 2018

Recognized as top 15% of all students in my program, apart of the Golden Key International Honour Society.

OCTOBER 20, 2020 EDWARD VAISMAN · RÉSUMÉ

Extracurricular Activity

Software Development Capstone Project (York University)

Toronto, ON

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER & DESIGN

Sept. 2017 - April. 2018

- Developed a new graduate application system for the EECS graduate department aimed to help review/find suitable graduate student candidates.
- Built using Express with Node.JS, MYSQL database and a Mochajs test framework.

York University ACM Programming Contests

Toronto, ON

Jun. 2013 - April. 2018

COMPETITOR

- Competed against fellow classmates to solve as many questions as possible.
- Able to apply several advanced topics such as Dynamic Programming and Greedy Algorithms.

CSGAMES (York University Team)

Montreal, QC 2016 - 2017

CORE MEMBER

- Competed alongside fellow classmates universities nation wide for the CS Cup.
- Participated in the following competitions: Mobile Development, Web Development, Theoretical Computer Science, Algorithms.